I'm going to take you behind the scenes
of how I edit a think media YouTube
video inside of Final Cut Pro I'm also
going to share some of my favorite
effects plugins and tools that I use as
well as some tips for saving time and
leveling up the edits in your videos you
got to just press record hey guys my
name is Nal with think media let's get
right into this video I'm going to take
you behind the scenes of how I actually
edit a YouTube video and I've had a
couple people ask me kind of what do I
do first and what do I do last so I want
to answer that question as well as tell
you guys everything that I use to make
my videos kind of stand out and look
professional now the very first thing I
do is organize my footage into folders
this is a must if you're trying to stay
organized and you don't want to lose
your videos because it will happen and
trust me get in the habit of just making
folders and keeping everything organized
now the easiest way to do this is
actually create a folder that's going to
be a template and then every time you
start a new project all you have to do
is copy that folder paste it into
wherever you want if it's going to be on
a hard drive or wherever you're going to
edit your video and then you're going to
retitle the name of this folder to the
name of your project it's those little
things that save you just a little bit
of time and as you edit for years and
years it saves you a lot of time now the
second step in my process is I start
cutting down my a-roll what you're
looking at right now me talking to the
camera this is considered my a-roll this
is by far the most boring part of the
process you just got to grind through it
and get it done there's really no
creativity with cutting out your
mistakes keeping all the good parts and
kind of trimming the ends just takes a
lot of time and it's really boring
however I just heard about a tool called
switch take that I am actually
experimenting right now for the very
first time and basically you can edit
live so as I'm shooting this video I am
keeping my good takes and I can also
Mark what takes are bad so when I import
it into Final Cut Pro all my bad takes
are going to be cut out automatically
and ideally if this works all great it's
going to save me so much time and so I
want to make a video on it if it does
well I'm going to leave a link in the
description where you guys can go and
check out that video because if this
works the I think it is this is going to
be a game Cher for editing and it's
going to save me probably a couple hours
a week now the past couple years without
this app what I've done is I've actually
just put all of my a-roll inside of my
timeline and then I just skim through I
see the audio waveforms and I just
listen to the first couple of words and
then I jump forward listen to the first
couple words because I mess up a lot and
my last take is always going to be my
best take so as I start skimming through
the video I can hear that I'm just
repeating myself because I messed up at
some point and so I'm starting that
sentence now I actually have a video
where I explain this in a bit more depth
and so I'll leave a link in the
description if you want to check that
out now the third step that I do in my
editing process is I watch my A- roll
all the way through and I analyze it now
the major tip here is you want to hit L
on the keyboard and this is going to put
you at 1.5 times speed that way you
don't have to listen to your video at
just a normal Pace cuz you already know
what you really said so just listening
to it at a faster pace is going to save
you time as well as I'm watching my
video I'm intentionally listening for
parts that might be boring or where I
repeat myself stuff that I want to
delete and think that it doesn't really
need to be in the video after that the
fourth step that I do is I add in my
b-roll b-roll are those clips that go
over the a-roll so right now as I'm
talking this is the a-roll and then I
add in these other clips that are a bit
more interesting and something for you
to look at as I talk about it so let's
say I'm talking about YouTube and I'm
talking about cameras then I'm going to
show you some b-roll about that now the
site that we've been using at think
media is story blocks.com and I do
recommend it because they have a huge
library and so for just generic stuff
you can find almost anything for what
you're looking for you're going to find
it on Story blocks.com the fifth step in
my process is I add in text effects and
Transitions and usually around this time
is when I go ahead and I add my end card
onto the end of my video this is
definitely where it starts to get a lot
more fun even with the b-roll and these
effects and transitions this is where
you get to kind of spice things up add a
little bit of that sauce onto your video
now there are some free built-in Final
Cut Pro effects that I use in a lot of
my YouTube videos and so I want to share
those with you guys as well as some of
the paid plugins that I think are
definitely worth it that you should
probably buy too some of the most common
ones that I use when it comes to these
YouTube videos is a crop in so right now
as I crop in my face I crop back out
this just helps kind of re-engage the
viewer and mix things up now the second
one I use it's a little bit more
dramatic and that's Ken burs this is
that slow zoom in or zoom out effect I
do this just inside of Final Cut Pro
using the Ken burs now this is actually
a new feature that Final Cut pro has
added which is a bit of 2D tracking so
right now I can add some text to my face
and move around or Graphics whatever I
want to do and this is a really cool
effect because it just spices things up
and it's super easy to do all you have
to do is grab your text hover it over
your face or an object that you want it
to track to then you analyze it and it
just sticks right to it let's talk about
some of the paid plugins that I use for
these think media videos one of the ones
I've been using more recently for these
videos is this title effect where you
see the titles come in and out this is
an effect called text animator and it's
by Esco now some of the newer plugins
that I recently got and I've been able
to play with on these think media videos
are from motion V effect now they
actually have a pack specifically for
YouTubers and these are pretty cool
because you get a little bit of
everything so you're going to get some
text you're going to get some popups
with your social media handles basically
everything you need to get started as a
YouTuber you could just go byy the m 3
kit and you're going to have a lot of
the stuff that you're going to need to
get started on YouTube and look like a
professional because it just drag and
drop it's really easy to use and
everything is customizable too so you
can go in there you can mess with the
duration mess with the In-N-Out
animations and I definitely recommend
buying it now there's a few other packs
that they have that I really enjoy one
of them is the m lowers bar and this is
a whole huge pack of lower thirds that
you can use in your videos and if you
don't edit videos you don't understand
how long it takes to actually come up
with something like that so being able
to just download this and buy it off
their sites and then drag it onto your
timeline and be able to just put
everything in there and it looks super
professional it's really cool and it's
going to save you a lot of time another
one I've been playing a lot with
recently is their M Tile kinetic 2 and
these are some really cool text effects
that you can add into your YouTube
videos one other thing to mention is
story blocks actually does have some
cool stuff that you can use if you want
a little subscribe button or a like
button this is a great way to go
especially if you already have story
blocks now I'm going to have links for
all of this stuff in the description
down below so make sure you go check
that out if you're interested in getting
any of this stuff now the sixth step in
my process is I edit the audio so I
added my music I added my sound effects
and I also go through and I do a little
bit of tweaks to the audio that you're
listening to right now I think media we
love using epidemic sounds they have a
great music library but they also have a
great sound effects Library kind of
twoin one so if you are looking for a
paid music site where you can still make
money and monetize your videos
definitely recommend epidemicsounds.com
the seventh step in my process is to
finalize my hook now the hook is at the
very beginning of the video and I like
to spend just a little bit of extra time
refining that hook because it is so
important for YouTube videos one of the
things that I like doing is adding in
captions to that beginning of the hook
so people can see what I'm saying and it
just is really engaging with the video I
like using the text effects from the
mtitle kinetic or from the text animator
and I use that to add a little bit of
Animation to my text so when it comes in
and comes out it looks all fancy my next
step is to go through and color grade
all of my footage from slog 3 to
something that I like like I use this
called Utopia from Phantom Luts in
their pack called Airy looks and I like
the look that it gives me just right
from the L then after that I go ahead
and I export my video and I watch it one
more time just to make sure there are no
more mistakes in the video if you're a
beginner and this is really exciting and
you want to be able to use plugins and
effects but you don't really understand
the basics yet so maybe it's a little
bit overwhelming I want you to click on
the screen and watch this video and I
walk you through Final Cut Pro 10 I show
you all the basics I show you everything
you need to know to get started as a
beginner and I will see you guys in the
next video
[Music]